XIAOYU A. GAO

13107 Meadow Hall Court, Herndon VA, 20171 | (703) 901-0568 | gao_xiaoyu@bah.com | iknowhtml.github.io | github.com/iknowhtml

Profile

I am a Full Stack Javascript Developer with a passion for technology and innovation. My experience and expertise ranges from designing and implementing responsive and user-friendly UX/UIs, architecting and developing modular, scalable and fault-tolerant back end infrastructures and devops pipelines using Agile development methodologies. In particular, I specialize in web such as React/Redux, Node.js/Express, Webpack, Docker, Terraform, Jenkins and AWS.

Education

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

August 2016

- Computer Engineering & Electrical Engineering
- Rodman Scholar (Honors Program for Top 5% of Engineers

Skills

Languages:

• JavaScript (ES5/ES6/ES7), Shell (Bash), Java (7/8), C/C++

UX/UI and Front End Web Technologies:

• Sketch, HTML5, CSS3, React, Redux, PostCSS, Webpack

Devops Tools:

• Travis, CircleCI, Jenkins, Terraform, Packer

Development and Testing Tools:

• Agile (Scrum), Git, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, ESLint, NPM, Yarn

Back-End Web and Database Technologies:

• Node.js, Express, MySQL, MongoDB

Infrastructure Technologies and Cloud Services:

Docker, AWS
 (IAM/VPC/EC2/S3/ELB/CloudFront/Route53), Azure
 (Storage/App Services/Function App/CosmoDB)

Work Experience

Booz Allen Hamilton - Technologist

May 2017 - Present

- Developed a proof of concept Blockchain application demo to replace existing transactions infrastructure for the U.S.
 Treasury.
- Front end built with React, Redux, React Router, Redux Form and styled with Spectre.css and custom CSS as a static SPA.
- Back end written in Node.js, and data is persisted on Azure CosmoDB as a MongoDB Database, as well as on the Microsoft's Blockchain.
- Smart contracts written in Solidity with Truffle and deployed to Microsoft's private Ethereum network.
- Infrastructure provisioned with Terraform, and front end and back end build and deployment automated with Jenkins.
- SPA and API deployed on Azure Blob Storage and Web Apps respectively, and Geth nodes hosted on Microsoft's Blockchain as a Service.
- Front end files stored in Blob storage proxied with Azure Function App Service to allow accessing static files as website URL.
- Architected the front end, back end and deployment pipeline, as well as the cloud infrastructure for the project.
- Led development efforts across the stack, including the UX/UI design, front end, back end and devops, in a small team of developers in an Agile environment using Kanban.
- Acted as defacto Product Owner and Scrum Master to translate requirements from the stakeholder, and to convert requirements into tasks to be distributed among team members.

Capital One - Technology Development Intern

June 2015 - August 2015

- Developed a sprint tracking web application that aggregates data from various tools such as VersionOne, Git/SVN, Hudson/Jenkin and SonarCubed in an user-friendly and responsive dashboard interface.
- Aided in the design of the UX/UI and implemented front-end logic to display data to users as well as validate inputs using AngularJS, Jquery, SASS and custom CSS.
- Developed RESTful APIs to allow communication between front-end and back-end using Spring Core.
- Deployed application to an internally accessible AWS server.

Booz Allen Hamilton - Research Assistant Intern

May 2014 - August 2014

- Developed an email filtration IDS web application for detecting malicious email content.
- Application performed full packet capture of SMTP traffic and static analysis of email pcaps and links using Bro-IDS and MASTIFF.
- Designed front-end interface using Jquery and Bootstrap and developed the back-end with Flask and SQLAlchemy.
- Application used to collect metrics on email traffic to improve incident response time for internal cyber security team.